









<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        
            <atom:link href="https://pbjwrites.info/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        
        
            <copyright>© PBJ</copyright>
        
        <description>PBJ Writes</description>
        
            <language>en</language>
        
        
        <link>https://pbjwrites.info/</link>
        
        
            <title>PBJ Writes</title>
        
        
        
            <item>
                
                
                    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="diagram-samples">Diagram Samples</h1>
<p>I have experience creating and producing diagrams, screenshots, logos, and other images with Microsoft<sup>®</sup> Visio<sup>®</sup>, Lucidchart, Adobe<sup>®</sup> Illustrator<sup>®</sup>, Adobe<sup>®</sup> Photoshop<sup>®</sup>, and Snagit<sup>®</sup>. The following examples show some of the variety of my work.</p>
<h2 id="relationship-diagram">Relationship Diagram</h2>
<p>A software application that I was documenting had an adjuster package that would adjust calculated values. The adjuster package has sets, rules, and qualifiers. I needed a way to depict the relationship between these three components of the adjuster package in order for users to grasp how to configure the adjusters. For instance, a set may have more than one rule but a rule can only have one qualifier. Another insight communicated in the diagram is that qualifiers do not need to be associated with a rule because a qualifier may have expired or is planned for the future.
<br></p>
<p>
















































    



    



    





    







    



    
    
    
    
    

    

    
    
    
    

    
        

        

        
    






<span class="paige-image">















<img  alt="Relationship Diagram"   crossorigin="anonymous"   height="1050"   referrerpolicy="no-referrer"  src="/../assets/diagram_sample_1.350c86d568e428268ce4064cf75cc06968683cad760c1cf539dda1134be90117.png"   style="height: auto; max-width: 45rem"    width="1138" >
</span>


</p>
<h2 id="document-workflow-diagram">Document Workflow Diagram</h2>
<p>As a new hire, I wanted to understand how my small software development team and I would produce user documentation. After a few months on the job, I was able to grasp the role that I needed to play but also the role that teammates would need to play in the user documentation life cycle. This workflow is what I presented to clear up any confusion about who does what, how user documentation is authored, the format of review documents, and how comments are documented.
<br></p>
<p>
















































    



    



    





    







    



    
    
    
    
    

    

    
    
    
    

    
        

        

        
    






<span class="paige-image">















<img  alt="Relationship Diagram"   crossorigin="anonymous"   height="1830"   referrerpolicy="no-referrer"  src="/../assets/diagram_sample_2.e7091a2c67f52ffe4abc6e9483a5124c3cf182ceac6f8a8a106565f2cfdf3dc6.png"   style="height: auto; max-width: 60rem"    width="2942" >
</span>


</p>
<h3 id="software-upgrade-by-environment-workflow-diagram">Software upgrade by Environment Workflow Diagram</h3>
<p>I worked a project that had a software application with two flavors—a forecast program and a real-time processing program. These two form factors shared a lot of code and resources since they essentially performed the same function except the forecast program processed historical data and the real-time program processed new, incoming data. Within these two programs, each had its own sub-environments. A need arose from technical teammates to understand how software upgrades would happen—where would they originate, what were the high-level steps, what to do if testing failed, etc. This workflow diagram accompanied a text description in a workflow document for the software.
<br></p>
<p>
















































    



    



    





    







    



    
    
    
    
    

    

    
    
    
    

    
        

        

        
    






<span class="paige-image">















<img  alt="Relationship Diagram"   crossorigin="anonymous"   height="2038"   referrerpolicy="no-referrer"  src="/../assets/diagram_sample_3.b6c897ccd5150dbb62a09cdb7aad5c6f777f81a8919d8767464fad112fa031fe.png"   style="height: auto; max-width: 60rem"    width="3448" >
</span>


</p>]]></description>
                
                
                    <guid>https://pbjwrites.info/portfolio/diagram_samples/</guid>
                    <link>https://pbjwrites.info/portfolio/diagram_samples/</link>
                
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                
                
                    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="editing-samples">Editing Samples</h1>
<p>I have prepared two editing samples each with a context cover page.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><a href="../../assets/attachments/editing_sample_1.pdf">Editing Sample 1</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="../../assets/attachments/editing_sample_2.pdf">Editing Sample 2</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]></description>
                
                
                    <guid>https://pbjwrites.info/portfolio/editing_samples/</guid>
                    <link>https://pbjwrites.info/portfolio/editing_samples/</link>
                
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                
                
                    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="how-to">how-to</h1>
<h2 id="use-this-template">use this template</h2>
<p>This procedure shows template users how to use the Microsoft Word template, shown in <a href="../../portfolio/word_templates">Word Templates</a> with <mark>Word for Mac</mark>.</p>
<p>The keys to using this template are:</p>
<ol>
<li>Always use the template Styles to format content; and</li>
<li>If copy/pasting text from an external source (i.e., another document), always paste as plain text (also sometimes referred to as <code>Keep Text Only</code>).</li>
</ol>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>IMPORTANT</strong><br>
Copying and pasting content (without pasting as text only) from another document can cause serious formatting conflicts in the document because new styles may be introduced to the existing template style set.</p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="use-this-template-to-format-regular-paragrpah-text">use this template to format regular, paragrpah text</h3>
<ol>
<li>Place cursor in desired area for regular, paragraph text.</li>
<li>From the Microsoft Word <kbd>Home</kbd> tab, click <kbd>Styles</kbd> &gt; <kbd>Para Txt</kbd>.</li>
<li>Type or paste text with <code>Keep Text Only</code> option.</li>
</ol>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>REMEMBER</strong><br>
After text is entered, highlight the text and navigate to the Styles pane to verify that the Para Txt style is applied—the applied style will have a bold highlight around it.</p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="use-this-template-to-format-figure-captions">use this template to format figure captions</h3>
<ol>
<li>After generating a figure caption, highlight the caption.</li>
<li>From the Microsoft Word <kbd>Home</kbd> tab, click <kbd>Figure Caption</kbd>.
<br>
















































    



    



    





    







    



    
    
    
    
    

    

    
    
    
    

    
        

        

        
    






<span class="paige-image">















<img   crossorigin="anonymous"   height="672"   referrerpolicy="no-referrer"  src="/../assets/how_to_use_this_template_to_format_figure_captions.bb47eff436b5222b68f54510588c12c176b686530e9a8cb4506cf7f6ea87b87f.gif"   style="height: auto; max-width: 40rem"    width="1124" >
</span>

</li>
</ol>
]]></description>
                
                
                    <guid>https://pbjwrites.info/portfolio/how-to/</guid>
                    <link>https://pbjwrites.info/portfolio/how-to/</link>
                
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                
                
                    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="style-guide-sample">Style Guide Sample</h1>
<p>In all my professional positions, I have contributed to a style guide or manual of some sort. I am posting my first style manual work which is a format and regulation guide for students to follow for their electronic theses and dissertations (ETDs).</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><a href="../../assets/attachments/guidelines_sample.pdf">Editing Sample 1</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]></description>
                
                
                    <guid>https://pbjwrites.info/portfolio/style_guide_sample/</guid>
                    <link>https://pbjwrites.info/portfolio/style_guide_sample/</link>
                
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                
                
                    <description><![CDATA[<p>Granted these are from the time of different screen sizes and at least seven years old but I worked with what I had at a public university to create instructions for graduate students to aid in the formatting and submission of electronic theses and dissertations (ETD).</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>NOTE</strong><br>
These videos were produced with Camtasia screen capture software.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This video assists students who may not be familiar with Microsoft Word with how to generate a table of contents automatically.























    























    


<div class="paige-youtube">
    























<div class="paige-video ratio ratio-16x9" >
    






<iframe  allowfullscreen   referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade"   src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0uaNYw0F4rU?hl=en&amp;modestbranding=1"   title="YouTube video" ></iframe>

</div>

</div>

<br>























    























    


<div class="paige-youtube">
    























<div class="paige-video ratio ratio-16x9" >
    






<iframe  allowfullscreen   referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade"   src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AdVQgbvToKY?hl=en&amp;modestbranding=1"   title="YouTube video" ></iframe>

</div>

</div>
</p>
]]></description>
                
                
                    <guid>https://pbjwrites.info/portfolio/video_instructions/</guid>
                    <link>https://pbjwrites.info/portfolio/video_instructions/</link>
                
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                
                
                    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="word-templates">Word Templates</h1>
<p>I have three Microsoft Word templates available for sharing. The first two I am sharing as PDFs. Why PDF, you say? Well, these are my works and if you like what you see then you can ask me about them. The first two are templates. These two were created recently and are posted in a generic format while the third template was created several years ago for a position in higher education.</p>
<ol>
<li>This template is used for technical documents such as design or architecture docs: <a href="../../../assets/attachments/doc_template_1.pdf">Doc Template 1</a>.</li>
<li>This template is used for reports or requests: <a href="../../../assets/attachments/doc_template_2.pdf">Doc Template 2</a>.</li>
<li>This template is a signature page form for students to plug into their theses or dissertations: <a href="../../../assets/attachments/doc_template_3.doc">Doc Template 3</a>.</li>
</ol>
<!---|#|Template Description|Link|
|-|-|-|
|1|This template is used for technical documents such as design or architecture docs  |[Doc Template 1](../../../assets/attachments/doc_template_1.pdf)|
|2|This template is used for reports or requests|[Doc Template 2](../../../assets/attachments/doc_template_2.pdf)|
|3|This template is a signature page form for students to plug into their theses or dissertations|[Doc Template 3](../../../assets/attachments/doc_template_3.doc)| --->]]></description>
                
                
                    <guid>https://pbjwrites.info/portfolio/word_templates/</guid>
                    <link>https://pbjwrites.info/portfolio/word_templates/</link>
                
                
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
